so let's see what pipelining is about so
let's say we have discovered oil
somewhere very far away and we have a
gas station somewhere and now we take a
bucket of oil give it to somebody to
carry 3 Days Later they're here and they
pour the bucket of oil here and now we
have a quarter of a tank of oil so we
need to do this about four times it's
going to take 10 days probably for us to
have enough oil to feed a car so clearly
the guy with the bucket approach is not
working well for us what does work you
have a long pipe and you start pumping
some oil into the pipe the front part of
the oil moves through the pipe takes it
several days to travel and after 3 days
we get a bucket of oil here so what's
the big deal the latency is still 3 days
the big deal is that after we have
filled the first bucket 3 days after we
sent the oil the second bucket of oil
comes right after it so pretty much once
we fill this Pipeline with oil we pump
some oil here and we keep pumping oil in
and the oil keeps coming out so the rate
at which oil is coming out is going to
be many buckets per day although it
takes 3 days for the first bucket to get
there so the idea of pipelining really
is that although the latency is long for
one unit of oil to get there we can be
having many units of oil in progress so
that when one comes out we can very
quickly get the next one and the next
one and so on pretty much we're not
moving buckets one at a time there is
many many buckets traveling at the same
time